[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Which of the following words is in singular form ?",
    "options": ["formulae", "agenda", "oases", "radius"],
    "answer": "radius"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Choose the correct sentence:",
    "options": [
      "All of it depend on you",
      "All of it are depending on you",
      "All of it are depended on you",
      "All of it depends on you"
    ],
    "answer": "All of it depends on you"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "“A rolling stone gathers no moss” The complex form of the sentence is-",
    "options": [
      "Since a stone is rolling, it gathers no moss.",
      "Though a stone rolls, it gathers no moss.",
      "A stone that rolls gathers no moss.",
      "A stone what rolls gathers no moss."
    ],
    "answer": "A stone that rolls gathers no moss."
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "A chart was appended to the report. Here ‘appended’ means-",
    "options": ["changed", "joined", "removed", "shortened"],
    "answer": "joined"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "The mother sat vigilantly beside the sick baby. Here ‘vigilantly’ is -",
    "options": ["A noun", "An adjective", "An adverb", "none of the three"],
    "answer": "An adverb"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "“A new offer of job was alluring . Here ‘alluring’ means-",
    "options": ["tempting", "unexpected", "disappointing", "ordinary"],
    "answer": "tempting"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "“who planted this tree here ?” The correct passive voice of this sentence is-",
    "options": [
      "By whom was this tree planted here ?",
      "Who the tree had been planted hereby ?",
      "The tree was planted here by whom ?",
      "By whom had the tree been planted here ?"
    ],
    "answer": "By whom was this tree planted here ?"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Frailty the name is women. Here ‘Frailty’ is :",
    "options": ["An adjective", "A verb", "An adverb", "A noun"],
    "answer": "A noun"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Education is enlightening. Here ‘enlightening’ is :",
    "options": ["A gerund", "An infinitive", "A participle", "A finite verb"],
    "answer": "A participle"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Choose the appropriate prepositions in the blank of the following sentence : The family doesn’t feel ____ going outing this season.",
    "options": ["like", "on", "in", "of"],
    "answer": "like"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Fill in the blank with appropriate use of tense “I couldn’t mend the computer myself, so I ____ at a shop.",
    "options": ["had it mend", "had it mended", "had mended", "did it mend"],
    "answer": "had it mended"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Use the appropriate article- I saw ____ one-eyed man when I was walking on the road.",
    "options": ["an", "A", "the", "No article is needed"],
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "The word ‘omnivorous’ means :",
    "options": [
      "eating only",
      "eating only meat",
      "eating all types of food",
      "eating grass and plants only"
    ],
    "answer": "eating all types of food"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Complete the following sentence choosing the appropriate option : It’s raining cats and dogs, so-",
    "options": [
      "Make sure you take an umbrella.",
      "Watch out for falling animals.",
      "Keep your pets inside.",
      "Keep the windows open."
    ],
    "answer": "Make sure you take an umbrella."
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "The phrase ‘Achilles heel’ means :",
    "options": [
      "A strong point",
      "A permanent solution",
      "A weak point",
      "A serious idea"
    ],
    "answer": "A weak point"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "He worked with all sincerity. The underlined phrase is-",
    "options": [
      "A noun phrase",
      "An Adverbial phrase",
      "An adjective phrase",
      "An infinitive phrase"
    ],
    "answer": "An Adverbial phrase"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "This is the book I lost. Here ‘I lost’ is-",
    "options": [
      "A noun clause",
      "An Adjective clause",
      "An adverbial clause",
      "None of the three"
    ],
    "answer": "An Adjective clause"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Which do you think is the nearest in meaning to ‘proviso’ :",
    "options": ["stipulation", "sanction", "substitute", "directive"],
    "answer": "stipulation"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Cassandra is a night owl, so she doesn’t usually get up until about :",
    "options": ["7 am", "11 pm", "11 am", "7 pm"],
    "answer": "11 am"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Select the word that is the most closely opposite in meaning to the capitalized word : DELETERIOUS",
    "options": ["toxic", "spurious", "lethal", "harmless"],
    "answer": "harmless"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "“Gerontion” is a poem by-",
    "options": [
      "W. B. Yeats",
      "Mathew Arnold",

      "Robert Browning",
      "T. S. Eliot"
    ],
    "answer": "T. S. Eliot"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Fill in the blank. ‘_____’ is Shakespeare’s last play.",
    "options": ["As you like it", "Macbeth", "Tempest", "Othello"],
    "answer": "Tempest"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "Who has written the poem “Elegy Written in a Country Churcyard” ?",
    "options": ["Robert Frost", "P. B. Shelley", "Y. B. Yeats", "Thomas Gray"],
    "answer": "Thomas Gray"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "Who has written the play ‘Volpone’ ?",
    "options": [
      "John Webster",
      "Ben Jonson",
      "Christopher Marlowe",
      "William Shakespeare"
    ],
    "answer": "Ben Jonson"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Shakespeare composed much of his plays in what sort of verse ?",
    "options": [
      "Alliterative verse",
      "Sonnet form",
      "Lambic pentameter",
      "Daetylic Haxameter"
    ],
    "answer": "Lambic pentameter"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "The repetition of beginning consonant sound is known as -",
    "options": ["Alliteration", "personification", "onomatopoeia", "rhyme"],
    "answer": "Alliteration"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "Which of the following is not a poetic tradition ?",
    "options": ["The Epic", "The Comic", "The Occult", "The Tragic"],
    "answer": "The Comic"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "What is a funny poem of five lines called ?",
    "options": ["Limerick", "Quartet", "Sixtet", "Haiku"],
    "answer": "Limerick"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "Who wrote “Biographia Literaria” ?",
    "options": [
      "Lord Byron",
      "S. T. Coleridge",
      "P.B. Shelley",
      "Charles Lamb"
    ],
    "answer": "S. T. Coleridge"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "Robert Browning was a ____ poet. Fill in the gap with appropriate word.",
    "options": ["Romantic", "Modern", "Victorian", "Elizabethan"],
    "answer": "Victorian"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "Othello gave Desdemona _____ as a token of love.",
    "options": ["Handkerchief", "Ring", "Pendant", "Bangles"],
    "answer": "Handkerchief"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "P. B. Shelley’s ‘Adonais’ is an elegy on the death of-",
    "options": ["John Milton", "S. T. Coleridge", "Lord Byron", "John Keats"],
    "answer": "John Keats"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "The comparison of unlike things using the words like on as is known to be-",
    "options": ["metaphor", "simile", "alliteration", "personification"],
    "answer": "simile"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "‘Restoration period’ in English literature refers to -",
    "options": ["1560", "1660", "1760", "1866"],
    "answer": "1660"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "‘The Sun Also Rises’ is a novel written by -",
    "options": [
      "Earnest Hemingway",
      "Charles Dickens",
      "Hermanne Melville",
      "Thomas Hardy"
    ],
    "answer": "Earnest Hemingway"
  }
]
